Philip K. Crowe Papers MS109
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Photographs, 1800 -- 1981; 1944 -- 1975; MS109.004; 5.8 Linear Feet; 36 Digital Object(s)
  - Autographed Photograph of Sir Oliver Goonetilleke, Governor-General Ceylon, 1956; MS109.004.046.00020 (Box 46)
    Photograph originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 28 of numbered photographs.
    People; Portraits; Goonetilleke, Sir Oliver
  - Asian Dignitary, 1957; MS109.004.046.00021 (Box 46)
    Photograph originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 31 of numbered photographs.
    People; Portraits; Crowe, Philip K.; Li, Zongren, 1891-1969
  - Correspondence from Herve Alphand, French Ambassador to the United States, 1958; MS109.004.046.00022 (Box 46)
    Originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 35 of numbered photographs.
    People; Letters (correspondence); Crowe, Philip K.
  - Group photo, 1981; MS109.004.046.00023 (Box 46)
    Photograph originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 35 of numbered photographs. Label crossed off. Item 24 attached to back.
    People
  - Philip K. Crowe fishing, 1970; MS109.004.046.00024 (Box 46)
    Originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 35 of numbered photographs. Attached to the back of item 23.
    Crowe, Philip K.
  - Certificate from the Explorer's Club, 1912 -- 1936; MS109.004.046.00025 (Box 46)
    Originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library.
    Certificate; image/tiff; Crowe, Philip K.
  - Dioecesis Trundhemiensis Pars Australis, (reprint of) original handcoloured map edited by Moses Pitt, 1640, 1800; MS109.004.047.00001 (Box 47)
    Authentication of the map as original 17th century print is dubious: Moses Pitt lived 1654-1696. Originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 38 of numbered photographs.
  - Certificate of Appointment, Ambassador of Ceylon, 1953; MS109.004.047.00002 (Box 47)
    Originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 8 of numbered photographs.
    Ambassadors; Crowe, Philip K.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969
  - Certificate of Appointment, Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East, 1954; MS109.004.047.00003 (Box 47)
    Originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 7 of numbered photographs.
    Crowe, Philip K.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969
  - Baie de Smeeremberg, original handcolored lithograph, 1839 -- 1842; MS109.004.047.00004 (Box 47)
    Originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 12 of numbered photographs.
  - Photograph of earthrise over the moon, signed by the crew of Apollo 8, 1968; MS109.004.047.00005 (Box 47)
    Originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 33 of numbered photographs.
  - Photograph of Buzz Aldrin and the flag on the moon, signed by the crew of Apollo 11, 1969; MS109.004.047.00006 (Box 47)
    Originally displayed in the Crowe Room in Ginn Library. Frame 32 of numbered photographs.
- Personal Ephemera and Memorabilia, 1928 -- 1975; 1936 -- 1975; MS109.005; 1.7 Linear Feet
  This series contains assorted items of personal ephemera and memorabilia dating from 1936 to 1975, including the passports of Crowe and Crowe family members, Crowe's personal calendars, postcards, genealogical information, Ethiopian art pictures, a framed certificate of membership to the Explorers Club, programs relating to Queen Elizabeth II's visit to Ceylon. There is also a coin collection from the Royal Thai Mint and a memorial volume on Henry R. Luce. Crowe worked for Luce, the founder of Life, Time, Fortune and Sports Illustrated, as director of travel advertising for Life magazine, 1937 to 1938, and as a member of the advertising staff for Fortune magazine, 1938 to 1941 and 1944 to 1948. There is also a framed letter from the French ambassador congratulating Crowe on being made an "officier" in the National Order of the Legion of Honor. There is also a mock issue of Time magazine created for Crowe by Molly and Charlie Whitehouse. A particularly interesting item is a container made from an Indian bison hoof. Crowe shot the bison in the Billigiri Hills, Mysore on July 24, 1956. This information is recorded on the lid of the Bison container.
  - Personal Address Books, MS109.005.042.00001 (Box 42)
  - Personal Calendars, 1961 -- 1973; MS109.005.042.00002 (Box 42)
  - Personal Calendars, 1957 -- 1961; MS109.005.042.00003 (Box 42)
  - Personal Calendars, 1963 -- 1975; MS109.005.042.00004 (Box 42)
  - Postcards, MS109.005.042.00005 (Box 42)
  - Postcards, MS109.005.042.00006 (Box 42)
  - Crowe Passports, 1928 -- 1966; MS109.005.042.00007 (Box 42)
  - Crowe Family Passports, 1953 -- 1973; MS109.005.042.00008 (Box 42)
  - Mock Issue "Time" Magazine, 1960; MS109.005.042.00009 (Box 42)
    Volume 18 of the diaries. Created for Crowe by Molly and Charlie Whitehouse.
  - Henry R. Luce Memorial Volume, 1967; MS109.005.042.00010 (Box 42)
    Crowe worked for Luce, the founder of Life, Time, Fortune and Sports Illustrated, as director of travel advertising for Life magazine, 1937 to 1938, and as a member of the advertising staff for Fortune magazine, 1938 to 1941 and 1944 to 1948.
  - Crowe Family Genealogy, MS109.005.042.00011 (Box 42)
    Bound volume consisting of records of the Crowe Family of Virginia, Kentucky, Indiana and New York from which Philip K. Crowe traced his descent.
  - Manuscript by Myron Lewis Scott, 1965; MS109.005.042.00012 (Box 42)
    Recollections of the life of David Bailey Dearborn.
  - Crowe Family Armorial Bearings and Genealogy, MS109.005.042.00013 (Box 42)
  - Order of Danneborg Negatives, 1975; MS109.005.042.00014 (Box 42)
  - King's Dinner Negatives, MS109.005.042.00015 (Box 42)
  - Order of Christ: Photographs and Negatives, 1970; MS109.005.042.00016 (Box 42)
  - Certificates, MS109.005.042.00017 (Box 42)
  - Ethiopian Art Pictures, MS109.005.042.00018 (Box 42)
  - Programs from Queen Elizabeth's Visit to Ceylon, 1954; MS109.005.042.00019 (Box 42)
  - Assorted Brochures, Invitations and Cards, MS109.005.042.00020 (Box 42)
  - Bison Hoof, 1956; MS109.005.043 (Box 43)
    A container made from an Indian bison hoof. Crowe shot the bison in the Billigiri Hills, Mysore on July 24, 1956 according to the information recorded on the lid of the bison hoof container.
  - Coin Collection, Royal Thai Mint, MS109.005.044 (Box 44)